Psychics
Mobgle Search
The Spirits and Such Consultation
Office's official homepage....
（ナレーション）
〝霊とか相談所〞の
公式ホームページ
Spiritual power-Mobpedian
100 ways to tell if a psychic is real or not
A psychic's advice to those living with the gift
[Psychics] Spirits and Such Consultation Office Homepage: Reigen Arataka [Exorcisms & Seances]
Psychic Jet | A relaxing spiritual life | Seasoning City Center
Let us introduce you to the best psychics | Rei Rei Hotline
Available 24 hours! ~SpiSpi Call Center~
[Psychics] Spirits and Such Consultation Office Homepage: Reigen Arataka [Exorcisms & Seances]
Psychic Jet | A relaxing spiritual life | Seasoning City Center
To much surprise, it became quite popular,
その反響は意外によく
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
The star psychic of the 21st century
who defeated The Dragger
Welcome to
Reigen Arataka's
homepage!
You are the
visitor here.
Hello, I'm Reigen Arataka,
the new star of the psychic world!
Don't try to do it alone. Come talk to me ! !
Honest billing and various courses available ! ! !
Spirits and Such Consultation Office Official HP
and a lot of requests for actual exorcisms
started coming in.
依頼される内容も―
Do you want to hear
the voice of your loved one again...?
Those able to do "seances"
are considered modern-day necromancers.
Why not put an end to
those pesky inheritance battles?
Those of you troubled with "spiritual harm,"
are they causing you trouble with your neighbors ! ?
"Rapping sounds"
"Paralyzed" when you're trying to sleep
"Poltergeists," etc..
Hello, I'm Reigen Arataka,
the new star of the psychic world!
Don't try to do it alone. Come talk to me ! !
Honest billing and various courses available ! ! !
Do you want to hear
the voice of your loved one again...?
Those able to do "seances" are considered
modern-day necromancers.
Why not put an end to
those pesky inheritance battles?
本格的な除霊が
増えつつあった
Those of you troubled with "spiritual harm,"
are they causing you trouble with your neighbors ! ?
"Rapping sounds"
"Paralyzed" when you're trying to sleep
"Poltergeists," etc..
Do you want to hear
the voice of your loved one again...?
Those able to do "seances" are considered
modern-day necromancers.
Why not put an end to
those pesky inheritance battles?
Your stiff shoulders may
be due to a spirit on your back...
See us when you're not feeling well
or for modern sicknesses
Spirit Photography Evaluation
I will also evaluate
any other possible cursed items
you have and exorcise them!
Advice About Stigmatized Properties
Deal with "psychological defects"
before you move...
In order to avoid real estate troubles
and protect the value of your property
Modern "Urban Legends"
The Dragger, Hanako-san,
Kashima Reiko, Red Raincoat...
Net lore: the modern form of urban legends
Your stiff shoulders may
be due to a spirit on your back...
See us when you're not feeling well
or for modern sicknesses
Your stiff shoulders may
be due to a spirit on your back...
See us when you're not feeling well
or for modern sicknesses
Your stiff shoulders may
be due to a spirit on your back...
See us when you're not feeling well
or for modern sicknesses
Your stiff shoulders may
be due to a spirit on your back...
See us when you're not feeling well
or for modern sicknesses
Executing the Exorcism ! !
We will do our best to reduce the spirit possessing you
Option A —  Trial Course  A Mere 2,000 yen (Tax Excluded) Outside Offer Period: 3,980 yen
Option B —  Serious Course  A Mere 5,000 yen (Tax Excluded) Outside of Offer Period: 8,980
Recommended
Option C — All-Out Course  A Mere 12,000 yen (Tax Excluded) Outside of Offer Period: 19,880 yen
Refer us to a friend now and get an extra 5% reduction!! Also get an add-on exorcism for 20% off!!
Behold, Reigen Arataka's elegant special moves!
Salt Splash
Banishing Salt Punch
Aroma Runaway Express
Essence of Life
Draft
Low
Carbs
But that also meant
…が その分
中には とても
引き受けられないような依頼が
that some of the requests coming in
were the kind that could never be taken on.
舞い込むこともあった
Mob Psycho
One Danger After Another
~Degeneration~
Again...
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
ですから―
No matter how many times you ask,
I'm not going to curse anyone for you.
人に呪いをかけるなんてね
何度 頼まれてもムダなんで
どうぞ お引き取りください
Please leave.
But you're a psychic, right?
Come on, don't be so spoilsport.
（男性客）
霊能力者なんだろ？
いいじゃねえか ケチケチすんなよ
I'm begging you. Curse this guy for me.
頼むから
こいつに呪いをかけてくれよ～
I'm afraid I can't.
引き受けられません
（男性客）
ふざけんな！
You can't be serious!
I traveled really far to come see you!
遠方から
わざわざ来てやったってのに！
Nobody asked you to.
そっちが勝手に来たんでしょうが
（男性客）
はあ？　なんだ その態度は？
What? Is that how you talk to a customer?!
Are they going to fight?
（モブ）
ケンカになる？
All right, all right! Fine, I'll do it.
分かった 分かった
しょうがないな　やりますよ
If there are
3 evil spirits,
the exorcism
fee on 1 of
them will be
on the house!!
Really?! I knew it'd be worth the trip!
本当か？　来たかいがあったぜ！
The Spiritual Compendium  17th Edition
~The Miraculous Unknown Psychic~
But this is the only time I'm doing it.
ただし 今日だけですよ
責任は一切 取れませんからね
And I won't be held responsible
for what happens.
Huh?
ハア～！
Keep this on your person at all times.
これを
肌身離さず持っていてください
Curse
The hell is this?
何だ これ？
It's a cursed, well, you know...
（霊幻）
呪いをこめたアレです
As long as you have that with you,
I'm sure something will happen someday.
それを持っていれば
いつか何かが起きるでしょう
Oh, I don't need any payment.
お代は いりません
ただし決して他言しないように
But just make sure you don't
tell anyone else about this.
I mean, I believe you,
（男性客）
信じてるけどよ
but if you're messing with me...
もし俺をダマしてるなら―
あんた 呪うからな
I'm going to curse you.
Man, he finally left.
（霊幻）
やっと帰った
I mean, I can understand hating someone
so much you want to curse them...
呪いたいほど憎い相手が
いるっつうのは―
分からなくもないがな
Do you have someone like that too, Master?
師匠にも いるんですか？
Nope.
（霊幻）
いや いないけど
Do you?
お前 いんの？
Someone I want to curse?
呪いたい人？　う～ん
Uh, you don't need to think
so hard about it.
（霊幻）
いや そんな深く考えんでも
Huh?
いませんね
Can't think of anyone.
Don't take so long, then!
You actually scared me!
ためんなよ　ビビらせやがって！
Anyway, was it a good idea
to give him that thing?
（モブ）
でも さっきの人
あれでよかったんですか？
Well, I just cooked it up on the spot.
まあ あれは口から出まかせだ
別に誰も困らないだろ
I'm sure it won't harm anyone.
Do you really think so?
（モブ）
本当にそうかな
I mean...
たとえ… たとえ それがウソでも
Even if it's a lie,
First in the world!
- Goku NERO -
0 Purine
0 Carbs
Alcohol 4%
Pork Loin Tonkatsu Bento
in his mind, he believes that he's
actually cursing someone.
あの人の中では
他人に呪いをかけたことになってる
Is he going to keep living
under that impression?
一生 そのまま生きていくのかな？
Isn't that rather frightening?
それって
とても怖いことなんじゃ…
（霊幻）
モブ… 珍しいな
Mob?
Reigen Arataka
The New Star of the 21st Century
That's rare... He's actually
voicing his own opinion.
こいつが自分の考えを持って
意見するなんて
Something's obviously bothering him.
いや こいつには何か
強く引っ掛かるものがあったんだ
Did I miss something?
俺が何かを見落としている？
Hello, this is Spirits and
Such Consultation Office.
はい 霊とか相談所です
This is the place.
（霊幻）
ここか
At first, I thought it was a stalker,
（女性客）
最初はストーカーかと思って
警察に相談したんです
so I talked to the police.
でも どうも
人間じゃないみたいで…
But it just didn't seem human...
It was staring at me through
the window the other day!
この間は 窓からのぞいてたんです
窓…
The window?
（女性客）
ハア…
Seasoning Moving Center
５階でベランダもなし　なるほどな
We're on the fifth floor,
and there's no balcony... I see.
エクボ いるか？
You here, Dimple?
The hell do you want?
（エクボ）
なんだよ？
Could you check things out
around this window?
ちょっと窓周り 調べてくれ
See if there's a rope or something
dangling from the roof.
（霊幻）
屋上にロープの跡でも
残ってるかもしれん
And why do I have to do this?
なんで俺様が…
Feel free to eat any evil spirits you see.
悪霊いたら 食っといてくれよ
モブ 何か感じるか？
Mob, do you sense anything?
Yes, though it's faint.
はい ほんの少しですけど
Nope, not a damn thing.
ないない　何の痕跡もねえよ
って なに窓 閉めてんだ こら！
Why the hell did you close
the window, you jerk?!
だが 被害内容は―
But there definitely
seems to be a stalker...
ストーカーのそれで
間違いない
What kind of interest would a ghost
have in a living woman?
幽霊が生きた女に興味持つのって
何が目的なんだ？
Beats me. It's pretty rare for spirits
to have any sexual desires left.
さあな
性欲が残ってる霊は
結構レアなケースだろうな
It's not like they can reproduce anymore.
そもそも生殖機能ないしな
But does love always have to
come with sexual desires?
（霊幻）
恋に必ずしも性欲が伴うか？
Actually, I don't want to
discuss this with you.
お前と こんな話を
したくないんだが
Right back at you, ya jerk.
こっちのセリフだ バカ野郎
Is this... a poltergeist?
これは… ポルターガイストか？
What do I do? It must be mad
I called you here.
どうしよう
きっと怒っているんだわ
霊媒師さんをここに呼んだこと！
Did it settle down?
収まったか？
窓の外！
Outside the window!
きゃ～！
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
Mob! Vaporize it!
（霊幻）
モブ 蒸発させろ！
これは―
That's...
a living person.
生きた人間ですよ
やはりストーカーか！
So it is a stalker!
ええい クソ！　姿を消しやがった
Damn it! He disappeared!
He's in the next apartment.
隣の部屋だ！
Who are these people? Why are they here?
It's not like I did anything wrong.
（隣人）
た… 確かに
I mean, yeah, I'm sorry I used an
out of body experience to spy on you.
幽体離脱で人様の生活
のぞき見したのは
悪かったよ
But I seriously fell for you at first sight!
でも 僕 本気で
ひと目ぼれしちゃったんだ！
I've never felt like this before...
I didn't know what to do.
こんな気持ちになったのは
初めてで
自分でも どうしたらいいか
そ… そう 本気なんだよ
Y-Yeah... I'm serious about this.
僕は彼女と つきあうんだ！
I'm going to go out with her!
Don't get in my way! I'll murder you!
邪魔すんなよ！
ぶっ殺すぞ！
Why, you—
この～！
You pervy peeping tom!
この陰気な出歯亀が！
Ow, ow, owie!
（隣人）
ぐあ～！　痛い 痛い！
Say no to violence! Let me go!
I'll call the cops, you bastard!
暴力反対！　助けて！
警察 呼ぶぞ この野郎～！
何 言ってんだ こいつ
What are you talking about?
I'm sorry! I was in the wrong!
I'll never do it again!
すいませんでした！
僕が悪かった　もう しません！
Please forgive me!
どうか許してください！
あなたを好きな気持ちは
本当に真心なんです！　だから…
My feelings for you are genuine, though!
So, please... p-p-p-p...
本当に
You're seriously...
You're seriously insanely creepy!
本当に超キモいわ お前！
あ～ 怖がって損したわ！
I can't believe I was scared of that.
So he tried to hide his stalking tendencies
behind a supernatural phenomenon.
（霊幻）
ストーカー行為を―
怪奇現象のせいにしようと
してたんだな
Don't try that at home, Shigeo.
マネすんなよ 茂夫(しげお)
Why?
（モブ）なんで…
（霊幻）ん？
Why does she feel so differently after finding
out it was a human and not an evil spirit?
正体が悪霊か人間かで
こんなに違うのか 分からない
I don't understand...
Man, he's got a lot on his mind today.
（霊幻）
今日は やけに
いろいろ考えてるな こいつ
Guess I'll pick his brain later.
あとで話を聞いてみるか
All right, let's head back
and grab some soba on the way.
よ～し いったん戻って
帰り ソバでも食うか？
ファ～ア
（モブ）
はい
Okay...
Oh, there he is!
（大学生１）
ああ！　来た来た！
We were waiting for you!
（大学生２）
待ってましたよ！
Hey, you sure got him working
a long part-time shift today.
おい バイト拘束時間 長(なげ)えぞ
Three jobs in one day?
１日で３件　ホームページ効果だな
That website is paying off.
We want to make some memories
before we graduate, man!
卒業前に
思い出作りがしたいんすよ
So, like, we want to go to some popular
haunted place and take a spirit photo.
で はやりの心霊スポット行って
みんなで写真を撮りたいって感じで
But it'd suck if we actually
ran into an evil spirit.
（女子大生）
なんかあったらヤバいんで
So they're just messing around.
（霊幻）
遊びか
まあ 否定するつもりもないが
But it's not like I'm
going to turn them down.
日時と場所は？
When and where?
Right now, my dude!
We've got a car waiting just outside!
今からっす！
外に車 止めてあるんで
They definitely don't have a plan in mind.
（霊幻）
こいつら 内定なさそう
What happened to getting there in
20 minutes? It's already been 30.
（霊幻）
本当に20分で着くのか？
もう 30分たつけど
I think it might take another 30.
あと30分くらい かかるかもっす
We might not have time for soba after all.
（霊幻）
ソバ食いに行けないかもな
So who the heck are you? His assistant?
（女子大生）
君は何なの？　助手君？
I'm a part-timer.
アルバイトです
You work part-time at a psychic's office?
That's hilarious.
霊能事務所でバイトとか
マジウケる～！　時給ってさ…
How much do you—
Mob!
（霊幻）
モブ！
不測の事態に備えて
気を集中しとくように
Concentrate. Make sure you're
prepared for the unexpected.
はい
Right...
Wow, you sound legit!
（大学生たち）
う～ それっぽ～い！
ヤッベえ モノホン！
We're here.
（大学生２）
着いたよ！
（大学生たち）
ウエ～イ！　イエ～イ！
（大学生１）
うお～！　雰囲気 怖(こえ)え～！
Yo! This place is creepy AF!
OMG! I'm so excited!
（女子大生）
メッチャ ワクワクする～！
マジ ヤバい
Holy shit, man.
Holy shit.
You sense any spirits?
（霊幻）
霊の気配は？
Faintly...
（モブ）
少しあるけど
Doesn't deserve to be
a popular haunted spot, though.
（エクボ）
“はやりの心霊スポット”って
ほどじゃねえな
All right, hurry up and
take that picture, please.
（霊幻）
は～い！　じゃあ さっさと
写真 撮ってください
（大学生１）
ち～っす
Got it!
I'm taking it!
（女子大生）
撮るよ～！　はい チー…
Okay, say chee—
Actually, could you take it?
っていうか 撮ってくんない？
I want to vehemently decline,
but they're customers, so what can I do?
（霊幻）
激しく断りたいが
依頼人だし しかたない
Okay, say chee—
はい チー…
Oh, hey, don't forget the flash!
（女子大生）
あ～ フラッシュよろしくで～す
Okay, say cheese.
（霊幻）
はい チーズ
（大学生たち）ウエ～イ！
（シャッター音）
We should head back.
My disciple's still in middle school.
そろそろ行かないと
弟子も中学生なもんで
Sure, thanks.
（大学生たち）
は～い どうもした～
お疲れさんでした
TYVM.
Thanks.
Also, regarding the fee...
え～と 報酬の件なんですけども…
What? Fee?
え？　報酬？
報酬って マジ何のこと？
What are you even talking about?
What? The fee for this job.
はい？　依頼のですけど
Nothing bad happened, and you
didn't even do anything, psychic dude!
なんも起きなかったし
霊能力者さんだって
なんもしてないじゃないっすか！
You really want us to pay you for nothing?
この場合 お金を払う必要
マジあるんすか？
それって詐欺ってやつじゃん？
Isn't that a scam?
Yeah, like, a total scam!
それじゃん！　詐欺じゃん 詐欺！
No pay, and then...
（霊幻）
支払い拒否からの―
現場解散だと？
Not even a ride back?
Yup. I'd say the unexpected just happened.
起きたな 不測の事態
（霊幻）
しかたない
公道に出てタクシー拾うぞ
Oh, well. Let's head out to
the road and hail us a taxi.
No soba tonight.
ソバは なしだ
Mob Psycho 100
Hey!
（杉本(すぎもと)）
おい！　おい ガキ！
Hey, kid!
シカトか？　おい！
You ignoring me? Hey!
Look at you, stumbling around.
You're in our way.
（杉本）
ダラダラ歩いてんじゃねえよ
邪魔なんだよ
But since you're here,
could you lend us some cash?
（細川(ほそかわ)）
つうか 金 貸してくんね？
Huh? But I don't have any.
（モブ）
えっ 持ってないです
Why you freakin' out?
なに ビビってんの？
Could you bring us some money tomorrow, then?
じゃあ 明日 持ってきてくんね？
Huh?
You heard the guy.
（杉本）
“え？”じゃなくて
Uh, Sugimoto?
おい 杉本？
（杉本）
ぼろろれれれ
（細川）
おい どうした？
Hey, what's wrong?
Why are you stripping, Sugimoto?!
なに脱いでんだ 杉本？
（杉本）
もきょきょきょきょ！
僕は天使だ～い！
I'm an angel!
杉本？
Sugimoto...
Dimple, stop! Stop that!
（モブ）
エクボ やめろ！　やめろよ！
Sugimoto... Are you okay?
杉本 大丈夫なのか？
I dunno...
分かんねえ… 何が起きたんだ？
What just happened?
仕切り直しだ
Let's try this again!
Hey, you little shit!
You were laughing just now, weren't you?
おい ガキ！
お前 今 笑ってただろ？
わ… 笑ってない
I-I wasn't!
Shut up! You get what this is, right?
うるせえ！
もう分かんだろうが！
We're mugging yo—
これはカツアゲなんだ
息が…
（杉本）うぐっ…
（細川）杉本？
Sugimoto?!
ほど… いて…
I'm okay! Let him go, Ritsu.
僕は大丈夫だから
ほどいてやってよ 律(りつ)
（影山(かげやま)律）
いいの？
なんか タチが悪そうだけど
You sure?
They seem like a bad crowd.
（杉本）
ぶは～！
Dude, what's wrong with you, Sugimoto?
（細川）
今日 ちょっとおかしいぞ 杉本
（杉本）
ハア ハア…
（郷田(ごうだ)武蔵(むさし)）
うちの部員に何か用か？
Did you need something from our club member?
Huh?
Wh-Who the hell are you guys?!
なっ なんだ てめえら！
無言で囲んでんじゃねえぞ こら！
Who said you could surround
me like that, huh?
Bring it on, you bastards!
上等だ この野郎！
ぶっ飛ばすぞ こら！
I'll kick yer asses!
おい！
Hey, stop squishing me, damn it!
そんなにギュウギュウに
押すんじゃねえぞ こら…
イテテッ！
ちょっと 出られないから
Hey, I can't get out!
Hey!
ちょっと～！
Um, I'm fine, so please don't fight.
あの 大丈夫なんで ケンカとかは…
そうだな
Fair enough.
Sugimoto!
（細川）
杉本！
You'll regret this, you jerks!
覚えてろ！　チクショ～！
You sure you're all right?
（鬼瓦天牙(おにがわらてんが)）
ホントに大丈夫かよ？
Yes. Thank you.
（モブ）
はい どうも
You need to know when to
fight back, Kageyama.
影山も少しは やり返さないと
相手は増長する一方だぞ
Or they're just going to try
to bully you even more.
I can't think of a good way to.
（モブ）
方法が浮かばないんです
Kick their asses with your
shadow leader powers.
お前の裏番パワーで
ぶっ殺しゃいいんだ
You don't have to waste your powers
on guys like them, Nii-san.
兄さんが あんなの相手に
いちいち“力”を使わなくていいよ
If they show up again, I'll get rid of them.
次 来たら 僕が追い返してやる
Raking bad guys over the coals is
what's good for them and society.
悪(わり)いヤツには
制裁を加えてやるのが
そいつと社会のためってもんだぜ？
自分でやっつけろよ 次は
Make sure you kick their
asses on your own next time.
You've got the power to do it.
“力”を持ってんだからよ
ハア…
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
What? You ended up with a spirit photo?
（霊幻）
え？　心霊写真が撮れた？
Yes... So we wanted to
ask for your help again.
はい それで
また お願いがあるんです
塩でも まいとけよ
Just throw some salt around.
I don't do volunteer work.
ボランティアは やってないんだ
We're really sorry! We'll pay!
すいませんでした！
お金は払います
内容は？
So what's the job?
We want to go back to that haunted place
これから もう一度
あの心霊スポットに行って
and have you make the ghost
in this picture disappear!
この写真に写ってる幽霊を
消し去ってください
I mean, I can exorcise that
photograph if you'd like.
その写真を除霊することは
できますけど？
We don't even need to go back to the place.
別に現場に行かなくても
No way! It's creepy enough
knowing that thing exists!
無理です
こういうのが存在するってだけで
気持ち悪くて！
消してください！
Please get rid of it!
So an exorcism request. Very well.
除霊依頼ね　分かりました
じゃあ コースを説明するので…
Let me explain the various options.
We'll take the most expensive one!
（大学生２）
高いやつでお願いします！
Looks like you got dragged out again.
また呼び出されたな
And your Sunday got ruined yesterday.
昨日は日曜つぶれたし
キレていいんだぜ
You can get pissed off about this, y'know?
Please wrap this up as soon as possible.
早速 お願いします
There're three of them.
３人います
They don't seem to be evil spirits, though.
別に悪い霊じゃなさそうですけど
We'll just have to take care of them.
They're scaring our clients.
まあ 依頼人が怖がってるから
しょうがねえな
除霊してやれ
Go ahead and exorcise them.
Please don't.
（父霊）
やめてください
The three of us are family.
私たち３人は家族なんです
We died in an accident and
lost our chance at a good life.
生前は ゆっくり暮らせぬまま
事故に遭いました
But now that we're ghosts,
we've been living here peacefully.
でも 霊になった今は
ここで穏やかに過ごしています
何の悪さもしていません
We haven't done anything wrong.
I just want... to stay with my
family a little bit longer.
もう少しだけ 家族と共にいたい
As soon as this desire is fulfilled,
we will disappear naturally.
この思いが晴れれば
自然に姿を消します
So I beg of you... Please, let us be.
ですから
何とぞ お見逃しください
Did you hear that, Master?
今の 聞きました？　師匠
Nope, not a thing.
（霊幻）
いや 俺には何も…
Their aura must be too weak.
霊気が微弱すぎて
Th-There's no reason to exorcise them.
じょ… 除霊する必要ないですよ
They said that they
wouldn't do anything bad.
悪さ しないって言ってますし
家族だし
They're a family.
（女子大生）
ちょっと！
Hello?!
We called you here because we
need you to exorcise them!
必要あるから頼んでるんですけど！
It's way too creepy knowing they're here!
気味悪くて しょうがないんだよ！
悪さする しねえは 関係ねえから！
Who cares if they do anything bad or not?
Not to mention, we said we'd pay you!
つうか
金 払うって言ってんじゃん！
Hurry up and exorcise them already!
（女子大生）
早く除霊しちゃってよ！
（大学生２）
あ～ ここにいるだけで鳥肌 立つ！
I'm getting goosebumps just standing here!
（女子大生）
気持ち悪い！　吐きそう！
It's so creepy,
I feel like I'm going to throw up.
What's the matter, Mob?
モブ どうしたんだ？
You've gotten rid of plenty
of evil spirits before.
今まで さんざん
悪霊を消してきたじゃねえか
These people just want to live in peace.
この人たちは
平和に暮らしたいだけなんだ
僕がそれを壊すなんてこと
したくない
I can't... I don't want to destroy that.
Just hurry up and do it already!
No one cares how you feel!
いいから さっさとやれよ！
お前の心情とか関係ないから
Sir, we asked for your help
because we really needed it.
（女子大生）
先生～！
私たち 本当に困って
依頼してるんですけど！
Our customers always take top priority.
依頼人の要望は最優先するものだ
However, if spirits deserve
as much respect as the living,
（霊幻）
だが 霊にも
生者と同等の尊厳があるとしたら
and the three here are truly
just a family living peacefully...
本当に そこで家族３人が
つつましく暮らしているだけなら
Then I can't make Mob do something as
heinous as barging in and dispatching them.
そこに土足で踏み入って
強制退去をさせるなんて
そんな外道を
モブに強いるわけにはいかん
But our clients' fear is real, too.
…が 依頼人の恐怖心も本物だ
What should I do?
どうする？　プロとして
As a professional, can I really put
the ghosts above the clients?
依頼人より幽霊を尊重するのか？
よお 旦那
Hey, man of the house.
I bet you've got plenty of
pent-up spiritual power.
あんた 秘めた霊力は
結構ありそうじゃねえか？
（モブ）
エクボ？
Dimple?
You gained that strength to
protect your family, right?
家族を守るために
蓄えた力なんだろ？
In that case...
だったらよ
Why not kill those three right now?
今すぐ ヤツらを
とり殺したらどうだ？
They won't have to exorcise you
if the clients are dead.
依頼人が死ねば
除霊をする意味も なくなるからよ
You want to live peacefully
with your family, right?
（エクボ）
家族と静かに暮らすんだろ？
Go on. What other choice do you have?
ほら やるしかねえって！
Darling...
（母霊）
あなた
Daddy...
（子供霊）
お父さん
I beg of you... Please let us be.
（父霊）
お願いします　お見逃しください
I cannot do something so horrific,
そんな恐ろしいことは できません
子供の前で…
especially in front of my child...
I see. Well, what're you gonna do, then?
（エクボ）
そうかよ　じゃ どうすんだ？
But we have nowhere left to run.
（父霊）
かといって
私たちには もう逃げ場もない
If you must go through with it,
we'll just have to accept it.
どうしてもというなら
受け入れるしかありません
But, please...
でも せめて
Please, I ask that you
let us all go together,
せめて 家族一緒の所に行けるよう
そう願います
wherever it may be.
Mob, are the spirits still saying something?
（霊幻）
モブ 霊はまだ何か言ってるのか？
You...
お前…
Hey... So what's going on?
あの… どうなってんすか？
A moment, please.
少々お待ちください
What's wrong, Mob?
（小声で）どうした モブ？
He's so against exorcising them
that it's making him tremble.
震えるほど
除霊したくないみたいだな
That much, huh?
（霊幻）
そんなにか…
Okay, got it. Let's skip the exorcism.
オーケー 分かった！
除霊はよそう
俺だって
命令してるわけじゃないんだ
It's not like I'm ordering you.
別にいいんだぞ
自分の感情に従って
It's okay to listen to your feelings.
Yup. You don't have to
take this so seriously.
そうそう もっと気楽に判断しろよ
You're plenty strong, Shigeo.
茂夫は強(つえ)えんだからよ
I don't think you understand...
（モブ）
分からないんだ きっと
ああ これはきっと
僕にしか分からないんだ
This must be something
that only I understand...
I mean, there's no way I can
go off my feelings alone.
だって
感情に任せていいわけがないんだ
I can't take this lightly.
気楽になんて…
If I truly decide to protect this family,
僕が この家族を守りたいと
思ってしまったら
that'll mean the clients will
have to get hurt instead.
今度は依頼人が
ケガをするかもしれないんだから
How long is this gonna take, damn it?!
（大学生１）
いつまでやってんだよ！
Who cares what the brat—
バイトのガキぐらい 言うこと…
うわっぷ！
（女子大生）
何？
はあ？　何すか これ？
塩？　は？
Yo, what the hell is this? Salt?!
This concludes the exorcism.
（霊幻）
今ので除霊は終わりだ
What?
（大学生１）
え？　ちょっ 待てよ
ホントかよ 今ので…
Wait, seriously?
That was it?
We're done here.
終わりだ
Uh, okay.
は… はい
Reigen? What's the matter with you now?
霊幻 どうした？　お前まで
So that's what's going on here...
Why didn't I realize it sooner?
（霊幻）
そういうことか
どうして気付かなかったんだ
He can do so much more
than an average person.
あいつは人より
できることが多いんだ
見えてる世界が はるかに大きい
The world he can see
is far bigger than ours.
Curses and spirits are a
part of Mob's daily life.
呪いも霊も
モブの日常とつながってんだ
Both the human and the inhuman
are equally close to him.
人間も それ以外も
あいつにとっては
同じような距離にある
Damn it!
クソ！　依頼が増えて油断…
It's all because I took too many jobs,
got complacent, and half-assed things.
雑な仕事をしたせいだ
Let's head back.
（霊幻）
帰るぞ
Want some soba?
ソバでも食うか？
Okay.
（モブ）
はい
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
You okay with that?
（エクボ）
あれで いいのかよ？
The New Star of the 21st Century
Reigen Arataka
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
You actually took money for just
throwing a bunch of salt around.
結局 地面に塩まいただけで
報酬 受け取っちまいやがって
What was I supposed to do?
しょうがないだろ
If I hadn't taken the money,
it would've been suspicious.
受け取らないと
逆に疑われるんだから
More importantly, you're sure
they weren't evil spirits, right?
それより
本当に悪霊じゃなかったんだな？
If there are
3 evil spirits,
the exorcism fee
on 1 of them
will be on the
house!!
Yeah. I tried to provoke him,
but he didn't turn into an evil spirit.
ああ 唆してみたが
悪霊には転化しなかった
If there are
3 evil spirits,
the exorcism fee
on 1 of them
will be on the
house!!
Why are you trembling now?
なに震えてんだ？
ファ～ア
Oh, you're yawning.
Man, you two are like night and day.
（エクボ）
あくびかよ　似ない師弟だな
Hey, you've got something on your back.
ん？　お前 背中に何か ついてんぞ
なに？
What?
（エクボ）
こりゃ 誰かに呪いを向けられたな
Yeah, someone definitely cursed you.
放っておくと どうなる？
What'll happen to me if I leave it alone?
You might slip on a banana peel at least.
バナナの皮で滑るくらいの不幸は
起こるかもな
That'd be enough to do me in
if I was on some stairs.
階段にあったら命取りだな
取ってくれ
Get rid of it for me.
Your attitude sucks, so nope.
態度が気に入らねえから断る
Please, I can't ask Mob to do this for me.
（霊幻）
頼む　モブには言えないことだ
恐らく昨日の依頼人が
本物の呪術者を雇ったんだろう
I bet the guy from yesterday hired
someone who could actually use curses.
All right, fine.
チッ しゃあねえな
If there are
3 evil spirits,
the exorcism fee
on 1 of them
will be on the
house!!
Reception
The New Star of
the 21st Century
Reigen Arataka
Spirits and Such
Consultation Office
He might be able to see
something more terrifying
（霊幻）
あいつは
俺たちにも見えないような―
than anything that we can ever witness.
本当に怖いものを
知っているのかもしれないな
The things he feared,
（ナレーション）
恐怖するもの 忌避するもの
and the things he avoided...
Mob understood that they
were different from the norm.
自分のそれが
世間一般とズレていることは―
Shampoo
モブにも分かってはいた
If I ever end up wanting to curse someone...
（モブ）
もし僕が 誰かを呪いたくなったら
If I ever end up using my powers for evil...
もし僕が犯罪に力を利用したら
If I ever end up wanting to
eradicate people rather than spirits...
もし僕が
“霊じゃなく人を退治したい”
なんて 考えてしまったら
I wonder if anyone will yell at me for it.
誰かが
僕を懲らしめてくれるのかな
Mob tried to think about everything
that happened over the past two days,
（ナレーション）
モブは
この２日間の出来事について
少し考えようとしたが
but perhaps out of exhaustion,
he immediately fell asleep.
疲れていたのか すぐ寝てしまった
Mob
We've been invited to a rich guy's house!
（霊幻）
金持ちのお屋敷に招待された
I smell a huge score!
デカい依頼のにおいが
プンプンするぜ
We're gonna make that money, Mob!
がっぽり稼ぐぞ モブ！
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 4:
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
第４話“中身　悪霊”
"Inside ~Evil Spirit~."
動画配信サービス？
もちろん 正しい判断です
Inside
~Evil Spirit~
A streaming service? But of course,
that's an excellent decision!